Guide to the David P. McWhirter papers, 1976-1984
McWhirter, David P. papers, 1976-1984
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
David P. McWhirter papers, 1976-1984
7317
David P. McWhirter
2.5 cubic ft.
Magazines, brochures, reports, manuscripts, bulk mailings, subject files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The David P. McWhirter papers relate to human sexuality in general and to homosexuality in particular. Subject files derive from sexuality and privacy commissions on which McWhirter served. The collection includes numerous typescripts of pornographic stories.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Magazines, brochures, reports, manuscripts of stories, files, bulk mailings and miscellany relating to human sexuality in general and to homosexuality in particular. Subject files derive from sexuality and privacy commissions on which McWhirter served. Collection includes numerous typescripts of pornographic stories. Many of the items were in the Mariposa Research and Education Foundation library.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McWhirter, David P., 1932-; Mariposa Education and Research Foundation.
Subjects:
Gay men.; Pornography.; Homosexuality.; Sex (Psychology).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PROVENANCE
Many of the items were in the Mariposa Research and Education Foundation library. The provenance of the pornographic manuscripts is not clear. The Bruce Voeller manuscript Murder at McGurk was transferred to the Voeller Collection, #7307.
RELATED MATERIAL
Bruce R. Voeller papers, #7307.
Several cubic feet of periodicals have been catalogued individually; clippings and straight magazines and newspapers were discarded.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Work
Box 1
Series II. Professional Service
Boxes 1, 2
Series III. Other Writings and Publications not by McWhirter
Boxes 1, 2
Series IV. Miscellaneous
Boxes 1, 3
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Work
  - The Male Couple, by David P. McWhirter and Andrew M. Mattison
    - The Male Couple, by David P. McWhirter and Andrew M. Mattison (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Male Couple publicity (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Publicity, Schedules, and Speaking Engagements for McWhirter and Mattison, Detroit and Chicago, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II. Professional Service
  - Speaking Engagements, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Association of Sex Educators, Counselors and Therapists (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Roundtable Outline: Sex and Sexual Dysfunction (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mariposa-sponsored Library Display on Sexuality in Literature (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - Board of Medical Quality Assurance Task Force on Physician Education in Human Sexuality, 1977-1978
    - Board of Medical Quality Assurance Task Force on Physician Education in Human Sexuality, 1977-1978 - Correspondence, Reports, Papers, Information (Box 1, Folder 7-12)
  - State of California Commission on Personal Privacy, 1982
    - State of California Commission on Personal Privacy, 1982, Correspondence, subcommittee reports, schedules, drafts of the final report, and other background written material (Box 1, Folder 35-48)
    - State of California Commission on Personal Privacy, 1982, Correspondence, subcommittee reports, schedules, drafts of the final report, and other background written material (Box 2, Folder 1-13)
    - State of California Commission on Personal Privacy, 1982, Commission recommendations, drafts, report errata; "Suggested issues for study by Commission," "Commissioner Biographical Data Forms," Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
    - McWhirter Commission Appointment Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Series III. Other Writings and Publications not by McWhirter
  - State of Oregon Department of Human Resources Final Report of the Task Force on Sexual Preference, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "A Sex Manual for Women (and men)" by Kathie Kelly, Carolyn Smith, and Bernie Zilbergeld (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Development of Exclusive Romantic Pair Bonds: Construct Validation of a Five Stage Theory," by John Raymond Sumerlin (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Community Attitudes on Homosexuality and About Homosexuals: A Report on the Environment in Norman, Oklahoma" (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Report of the Committee on Homosexual Offenses and Prostitution," Home Office, Scottish Home Department (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "An Ounce of Prevention: Toward an Understanding of the Causes of violence," State of California Commission on Crime Control and Violence Prevention (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Homosexuals in America.. ." The Gallup Opinion Index (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Are There Gay People Working on My Business?" (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Second Annual Report of the Pennsylvania Council for Sexual Minorities (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Report of the Pennsylvania Council for Sexual Minorities (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Clippings and Articles Pertaining to Homosexual Legal Matters (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Recognizing Sexual Orientation and Gay People Within the Secondary Curriculum: What Role for Schools?" by Dickson J. Hingson (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Booklets on Kaposi's Sarcoma and AIDS (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "The Birth of Sexology - A Brief History in Documents" (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Breast Feeding," Scientific American April 1984 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Reports and Articles on Sexuality (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material on Sexual Topics (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - "The Freedom of Intimate Association," by Kenneth L. Karst (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Law in a Free Society" (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Articles on Privacy (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Secret Meeting Laws and Public Agencies" (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Background Material Pertaining to Privacy (Box 2, Folder 18-21)
  - Bibliography on Privacy (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Alternate Relationships and Families (Box 2, Folder 26-31)
  - "An Interim Evaluation of DSM-III Categories Paranoid, Schizoid, and Schizotypal Personality Disorder," by Larry Siever and Kenneth Kendler (Box 2, Folder 32-24)
  - "The Lavender Couch: A Consumers' Guide to Psychotherapy for Lesbians and Gay Men," by Marny Hall (Box 2, Folder 35-38)
  - "Gaze Aversion as an Unobtrusive Measure of Homophobia," by Robyn S. Zeiger (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "Urban Mexican Male Homosexual Encounters: An Analysis of Participants and Coping Strategies," by Joseph Michael Carrier (Box 2, Folder 40-44)
- Series IV. Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence and a Manuscript of Poems from Robert I. McQueen (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - International Transpersonal Association (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Numerous Typed, Mimeographed, and Carbon Copied Manuscripts of Pornographic Prose Fiction, Plus Illustrations (Box 3, Folder 1-23)